

Tim KuntzeHannemannstr. 77
12347 Berlin

+49/160 834 15 07 timkuntze@gmx.de

Portfolio: <u>tim-kuntze.developerakademie.com</u> GitHub: <u>https://github.com/TimKuntze/</u>

Tim Kuntze Frontend Developer

About Me

I am a Frontend developer, trained by a professional software development school called <u>Developer Akademie</u>. Before I decided for this big career change during Corona times, I worked about 10 years in Marketing for companies like Amazon.de, ATOSS Software and shyftplan, where I already had many contact points with the IT and Product Management teams. Since I started programming in summer 2020, I built several Frontend projects alone and in groups, that you can find in my public portfolio on my homepage or on GitHub. I love to combine my experience in the marketing and product management sector, especially regarding UX, with my acquired development skills.

Main Stack:

- JavaScript, TypeScript (Angular)
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material Design

Side Stack:

- Firebase
- REST-APIs, Unit-Testing
- Design/UX focused

Skills

- **Building Applications with JavaScript:** Built several Web-Applications, Jump-and-Run-Games and Responsive Websites.
- Using Angular to build material design applications: Built a CRM prototype and a progressive Web-App.
- Software-Project Management: Understanding Scrum & Agile Project
 Management, using agile principles while developing applications in group
 projects.
- **Working in a Software-Team:** During learning coding, I did several group projects where I learnt how to develop a software project in a team.

Professional Experience

shyftplan / (Senior) Marketing Manager

APRIL 2020 - PRESENT, BERLIN

- Owner of all SEA, SEO & HubSpot activities
- Responsible for all marketing reports (Salesforce and Tableau)
- Content creation for a variety of marketing channels (whitepaper, social media/social selling, landing pages, webinars)

ATOSS Software / Marketing Manager

NOVEMBER 2016 - FEBRUARY 2020, BERLIN

- Owner of all marketing measures for the branches healthcare, manufacturing, service industries and all existing customers
- Conception and A/B-testing for UX- and SEO-friendly landing pages

Netzathleten Media / Technical Ad & Campaign Manager

FEBRUARY 2014 - OCTOBER 2015, MUNICH

- Accounting, optimization und reporting of online advertising campaigns
- Technical integration of partner websites into the network

Amazon.de / (Junior) Content Manager in Video Games department

APRIL 2011 - JUNE 2013, MUNICH

- Planning, realization and evaluation of advertising campaigns for Activision Blizzard, Nintendo, EA and more with budgets up to 500k Euro
- Active involvement in the launch of the Amazon.de App

Education

Developer Akademie / Front-End Developer Training

JULY 2020 - Present, Online Course

- Project based coding academy. Main Stack: JavaScript, Angular.
- Portfolio: <u>tim-kuntze.developerakademie.com</u>
- Extensive Coding School, Learning Frontend Development, Coding, Agile
 Project Management and building several projects in teams and alone.

Fachhochschule für angewandtes Management / Diploma in Economic Psychology (FH)

OCTOBER 2005 - OCTOBER 2010, ERDING

 Diploma thesis: "Future-oriented advertising methods in the field of dialog marketing" (grade: 1,7)

Languages

German: native speaker, English: fluent

References

Junus Ergin (Software Development Coach); <u>junus@developerakademie.com</u>